Contact

dandrews412@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-andrews-30587094 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership Public Speaking Nonprofits

Languages

German English

Certifications

Daniel P Andrews

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Adult) (CCRN-A)
Registered Nurse

Advanced Cardiac Life Support
Basic Cardiac Life Support

Daniel Andrews

RN, BSN, CCRN at New York-Presbyterian Brooklyn Methodist Hospital

New York, New York

Summary

To see physical, emotional, and spiritual life transformation by optimizing organization mission and vision implementation. Any current or former organization I have had the honor of collaborating with impacts both local and global communities.

This summary is evidenced by my seven total years of advocating for and implementing best practices as a Registered Nurse in the critical care setting. Additionally, I have worked or volunteered for National Community Church in Washington, DC for three years where I encouraged, equipped, and empowered those affected by and passionate about social injustices (chronic homelessness, human trafficking, and inequitable access to healthcare and food). These experiences led to a pursuit and completion of a Masters of Divinity from Regent University with an emphasis in Marketplace Ministry (non-profit management).

Myers Briggs: ENFJ - The Teacher

Strengths Finder: Developer, Restorative, Achiever, Connectedness,

Individualization

Enneagram: Type 1, Wing 2

Experience

New York-Presbyterian Hospital MICU/SICU RN, BSN, CCRN, M. Div February 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Brooklyn Methodist

Mount Sinai Health System
Travel Registered Nurse
September 2018 - January 2019 (5 months)
Brooklyn

-Travel contract ending January 2019 at Mt. Sinai Brooklyn

Page 1 of 5

-Immense level of nursing and critical care patient advocacy potentiated while on this assignment

The George Washington University Hospital Registered Nurse
October 2017 - July 2018 (10 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

- -Implemented evidence based practices that elicited quality, holistic care to critical care patients and their families
- -Endorsed organization mission and vision while advocating for best patient and family outcomes
- -Contributed to Interdisciplinary team rounding, which optimizes achieving short and long term patient goals
- -Specialty areas include trauma, neurology, medical, surgical, kidney transplant, and cardiopulmonary

MedStar Health Registered Nurse July 2017 - October 2017 (4 months)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

This brief experience providing care in an urgent care setting was positive. I triaged approximately 75 patients a day with multitudes of chronic conditions and coincidently acute exacerbations of those conditions. After a short time it was evident however that if working as a nurse the Critical Care setting was were I was meant to be. I therefore returned to the ICU at George Washington University Hospital.

VIDA Fitness & Aura Spa Membership Consultant December 2016 - July 2017 (8 months) Washington D.C. Metro Area

Educated prospective members on the value and variety of VIDA which leads to positive, tangible, holistic wellness outcomes. This is an ongoing relational rapport that begins with joining and is cultivated for the remainder of the individuals' membership with intentional emphasis on preventive healthcare measures. This manifests via membership retention and positive short and long term heath outcomes for members.

This role also involved establishing, optimizing, and retaining corporate and residential accounts, where qualitative and quantitative variables

demonstrating positive outcomes are being experienced and projected. Other objective matters included meeting sales goals per month individually, as a consulting team, and interdepartmentally.

Finally, this role involved exceptional data management and speaking skills, primarily when reaching out to prospective individual members and establishing, optimizing, and retaining corporate accounts. Systems included Microsoft Office, Lead Dolphin, and Data Trak.

The George Washington University Hospital Registered Nurse, Critical Care November 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 2 months) Washington D.C. Metro Area

- -Implemented evidence based practices that elicited quality, holistic care to critical care patients and their families
- -Endorsed organization mission and vision while advocating for best patient and family outcomes
- -Contributed to Interdisciplinary team rounding, which optimizes achieving short and long term patient goals
- -Specialty areas include trauma, neurology, medical, surgical, kidney transplant, and cardiopulmonary

National Community Church

Youth Ministry Assistant (Independent Contractor) April 2016 - October 2016 (7 months)

- -Communication strategy and management
- -2016 Mission Camp Community Service Coordinator (10 organizations, 72 students)
- -Assist with weekly gathering execution
- -Yearly planning and calendaring for 2017 alongside Youth Pastor
- -Volunteer and student data management (background checks, policy agreements, attendance, contact information, etc.)

Ebenezers Coffeehouse

Barista

September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months)

- -Advocated the mission and vision of coffee with a cause
- -Provided quality customer service and established positive rapport with patrons

-Empowered customers to make sound purchase decisions through product education

National Community Church Local Missions Protégé September 2014 - August 2015 (1 year)

A year dedicated to personal character, community, and professional development within the marketplace. Working specifically in the A1:8 Missions department addressing social injustices such as homelessness, child advocacy, under-resourced youth, under-developed communities, and inequitable access to healthcare and food.

Key Accomplishments:

- -Implemented mission and outreach strategies across four NCC locations
- -Contributed to community needs and assets assessment
- -Assisted formalizing partnerships for the DC Dream Center
- -Organized and implemented communication strategies for local service opportunities
- -Mobilized 66 volunteers for a Thanksgiving meal for 100 people experiencing homelessness
- -Empowered youth at the Southeast White House (SEWH) through various programs
- -Facilitated SEWH teen forums and a small group for those experiencing homelessness
- -Co-led short term mission teams to Ukraine and Germany
- -Cultivated public speaking skills and pastoral emotional intelligence while shadowing an NCC Campus Pastor
- -Initiated and created educational opportunities for positive engagement with individuals experiencing homelessness

Medical Solutions
Travel Registered ICU Nurse, BSN, RN
February 2014 - August 2014 (7 months)

UPMC

Registered Nurse, BSN, RN January 2011 - February 2014 (3 years 2 months) Greater Pittsburgh Area -Elicited the power of communication as a charge nurse managing 22 critical care patients and a team of 13 nurses (specifically while at UPMC Shadyside MICU/CCU)

Education

Regent University

Master's Degree, Master of Divinity with an emphasis in Nonprofit Management · (2015 - 2018)

University of Pittsburgh - School of Nursing
Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2007 - 2010)